#### Contact

8008123027 (Mobile) rkundu01@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kunduritu (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Planning & Scheduling Leadership Communication

### Languages

English (Full Professional)
Hindi (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Web Programming using Java
Assessing Digital Maturity
Cloud Architecture: Core Concepts
Building and Managing a
Cybersecurity Program
Leveraging Cloud Computing for IoT

# Ritu Kundu

A delivery focused Program Director with extensive experience in delivering business change while leading large complex program of works involving multiple cross functional teams

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

# Summary

A very open and adaptable senior-level executive with 20+ years of experience managing application development and maintenance projects in a global delivery model as Senior Program Manager. My continual focus on operational effectiveness and delivery excellence have increased customer satisfaction, business opportunities, and improved profitability. Over my career, I've gained deep experience in strategic planning and management, developing business-aligned scalable offshore delivery units, solutions, program management, and operations. My career has spanned across consulting & development services in varied domains. Global service delivery has been a large aspect of my career. Seeking senior leadership roles where I can contribute to Business, improve processes, Operations Management and Strategy Definition

# Experience

50% GM)

Ness Digital Engineering
Program Director
September 2021 - Present (2 years 2 months)
Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Working closely with S&P Global for the digital transformation journey of their Products. Co-managing the delivery of multiple engagements for different divisions of S&P Global and successfully delivering business-critical Programs. Managing

Ratings: Platform Migration, Issuer Engagement, and Workflow and Control
Program – 200+Members (20M+ Revenue with 45% GM)
Commodity Insight - Staff Augmentation – 10+Members (200K+ Revenue with

Tetrasoft Inc.
Senior Program Manager
December 2020 - September 2021 (10 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Working closely with Chubb for the digital transformation journey of Chubb Products like (Speed to Market, Renewal Framework) and platform. Driving Adoption projects like DC-Radar live Integration, EP2BizPack, Bond Phase 2, etc...

Virtusa

Senior Delivery Manager November 2015 - August 2020 (4 years 10 months) Hyderabad Area, India

Handled projects mostly involving Agile and Iterative development methodology.

Strong Program/Project Management experience which includes managing the project's triple constraints (scope, schedule & and cost), Quality assurance and control, Risk Management, Stakeholder Management, Change Management, and Communications Management. Effectively monitoring and controlling various project/program activities and taking them to timely closure.

Worked extensively in the Global Delivery Model.

Excellent communicator with relationship-building and interpersonal skills. Strong analytical, problem-solving, and organizational abilities. Possesses a flexible and detail-oriented attitude with a customer focus.

Extensive experience in managing large and complex programs (150 FTE (10+ Million Annual Revenue)) and delivering them on schedule, within budget along with high quality.

Handling account-level operations including P/L Mgmt., People Mgmt., driving Process Metric/Revenue/OM goals, Quality Reviews, Proposals, and contract Mgmt.

Organizational Responsibilities:

Delivery, P&L, and Customer Service

No Code Reds in any project

Project Responsibilities:

Transition Management – Pega Projects for Macquarie Securities: Knowledge transition and successful sign-off from customer

Delivery Management – Pega Projects for Link Group: Application

Development in Agile – Successfully delivered Code Red Projects under Link

Group (Client Accounting, Group Finance, and CRs on Client Accounting) by

Kewill Senior Project Manager

setting up the team at offshore

#### September 2012 - November 2015 (3 years 3 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

- Headed Center of Excellence QA
- Active member of the Global QA Management team for process improvements in the entire Kewill QA organization. I traveled to the UK for a Global QA Meet and established Global Test Automation Service Initiatives.
- Early adopters for Kewill Agile methodology with Confluence, JIRA, and Test Link tools to get full visibility of releases of products over the products available in global locations.
- Successfully implemented Quality and Release Management processes for all product releases within Kewill.
- Defining and establishing the processes for Global Test Automation as a Service for all products
- Introduced tools and processes to get code coverage and functional coverage on testing and achieving 80% code coverage and functional coverage with Test Automation.
- Effectively manage a team of on and off-shore test performance and automation engineers, allowing them to be impactful in their roles.
- Define and implement technical strategy.
- Achieved 15% in cost savings for COE.
- Created metric report including traceability for QA Group.
- Introduced Achievement and Reward into the team performance.
- Interact with Overseas Customers regularly to make QA more proactive and business-focused.
- Created a QA Dashboard for CXO-level reporting.
- Reduced Attrition by cross-training resources on different products as well as on Automation.

#### **Thomson Reuters**

Project Manager

December 2009 - August 2012 (2 years 9 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Project Management of multiple business-critical releases for One Source Income Tax (OIT) product. Built and led a team of 25 from scratch for India Initiative for Performance and Scalability of ONESOURCE Income Tax (OIT) Products. Handled the overall project lifecycle and delivery of US-based projects under OIT. Worked on the project execution from project initiation to project closure using Agile Methodology. Used time tracking, status tracking, sprint demos after each module release, and monthly status reports to keep the projects on course. Performed project-related planning (Scope

Management Plan, WBS, Resource Management Plan, Risk Management Plan, and Quality Management Plan) as well as monitoring and controlling project execution for all the projects undertaken by the OIT Hyderabad Team. Carried out team development, appraisals, talent management, recruitment, selection, career development, and successor planning for the team members to keep the team motivated and on course to be highly productive. Rendered support to the team in gaining product knowledge in the minimal time possible. The team started being productive within a couple of months. Monitored and controlled risks and scope changes so as to minimize the cost and time impact using budgeting methodology. Received many appreciations and Best Team Awards on projects from end customers for quality control and vendor management.

HCL Technologies
Project Leader
June 2006 - December 2009 (3 years 7 months)
Noida Area, India

Technical Skills: .NET Technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server)
Assignments Handled
Application Development and Maintenance for Reader's Digest:
Application Development and Maintenance for CEVA
Resource Management System
Sampling Approval Dashboard
Compliance Tracking System

Sapient Senior Software Engineer January 2006 - June 2006 (6 months) Gurgaon, India

Worked on 2 development projects in .NET Technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server) for Royal Bank of Scotland, UK, naming RBS ICE PC Apps and RBS ICE EOD Feeds Framework

Mphasis Senior Software Engineer July 2005 - December 2005 (6 months) Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Worked on development projects in .NET Technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server) - SmartApp project team for Uchida Spectrum, Japan

### **Protech Engineers**

Software Developer

June 2000 - June 2005 (5 years 1 month)

Worked on development projects in .NET Technologies (C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server) - Production Analysis System (PAS), Reporting Tool, Time Office & Personnel Management System (PMS), Customer Request Management (CRM)

### Education

Kurukshetra University

Postgraduate Degree, Computer Science · (1998 - 1999)

Kurukshetra University

Master of Science - MS, Operations Research · (1996 - 1998)

Kurukshetra University

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Computer Science · (1993 - 1996)